For the first time... the vast, spectacular drama that changed the world!
The Message is a adventure, drama, action film directed by Moustapha Akkad.
In sixth-century Mecca, Prophet Muhammad receives his
first revelation from God as a messenger.
Three years later, he's not alone in his quest and
publicly declares his prophecy.
Muhammad is fought by Abu Sufian and his wife Hind, rulers of Mecca.
Muhammad's followers are hunted and tortured but he continues his calling.
Hamza, played by Anthony Quinn.
Hind, played by Irene Papas.
Abu Sufyan, played by Michael Ansara.
Bilal, played by Johnny Sekka.
Khalid, played by Michael Forest.
Ammar, played by Garrick Hagon.
The Message (Arabic: الرِّسَالَة, romanized: Ar-Risālah) originally known as Mohammed, Messenger of God (Arabic: مُحَمَّد رَسُول‌ الله, romanized: Muḥammad Rasūl
Allāh) is a 1976 epic film directed and produced by Moustapha Akkad that chronicles the life and times of Muhammad, who is never directly depicted.
Released in separately filmed Arabic- and English-language versions, The
Message serves as an introduction to the early history of Islam.
The international ensemble cast includes Anthony Quinn, Irene Papas, Michael Ansara, Johnny
Sekka, Michael Forest, André Morell, Garrick Hagon, Damien Thomas, and Martin Benson.
It was an international co-production between Libya,
Morocco, Lebanon, Syria and the UK.
The film was nominated for Best Original Score in the 50th Academy Awards, composed by
Maurice Jarre, but lost the award to Star Wars (composed by John Williams).
The film explores themes of middle east, muslim, islam, religion, muhammad.
The tone is emotional.